Md Rakibul Hasan Molla

Software Engineer



in rakibcseku 🔘 rakib06

Profile

professional skilled Experienced ΑI developing RESTful APIs, automation with Python and Selenium, chatbots using NLP and deep learning models, speech recognizer using Kaldi, document/PDF extractors, and image processing algorithms. Collaborates effectively cross-functional with teams, conducts experiments, fine-tunes models, and contributes to open-source AI projects.

Education

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering,

Khulna University 🛮

2016 - 2020 | Khulna, Bangladesh

CGPA: 3.09

Professional Experience

Software Engineer, BRAC IT Services Ltd. □

2021 - present | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Led a team of Python developers in the development of a data analytics, automation and chatbot platform for a major client
- Developed RESTful APIs using Django Rest framework to support various applications and services
- Created task automation tools using Selenium, PyAutoGUI, and Machine Learning to improve efficiency and reduce manual labor
- Designed and developed a chatbot using NLP and deep learning models, such as LSTM and Transformer, to improve customer engagement and support
- Built document and PDF extraction tools using OpenCV and Tesseract OCR to facilitate data processing and analysis
- Utilized image processing and computer vision techniques using OpenCV, PIL, and Scikit-image to develop image recognition and analysis applications
- Worked on machine learning projects using TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, and Scikit-learn to develop predictive models and analysis
- Implemented multiprocessing to optimize project performance resulting in a 4-6x increase in processing speed
- · Collaborated with cross-functional teams to problems solve complex and drive innovation

Machine Learning Engineer, Evaly.com Ltd □ 2021 - 2021 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Developed a recommender system using Apriori algorithms to enhance the user experience and increase sales
- Conducted data analysis and manipulation using PySpark and Pandas to support various business needs
- Worked with the development team to integrate the recommender system into the E-commerce website
- Conducted extensive testing and validation to ensure the accuracy and reliability of the recommender system

Expertise

Programming Languages (Python, Java, JavaScript),

Database (SQL, MySQL, MongoDB), **Backend Development** (Django, Flask), **Frontend Development** (ReactJS, Redux, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS),

Test Automation Tools (Selenium, Karate, Cucumber),

Machine Learning Frameworks/Toolkit (TensorFlow, Keras, PyTorch, Scikit-learn, Kaldi, Rasa),

Automation Tools (PyAutoGUI, Python-Selenium),

Data analysis and manipulation (Pandas, PySpark),

Chatbot development (RASA and other NLP libraries:),

Recommender system development (Collaborative filtering and Apriori algorithm), Version control (Git/Github, GitLab), Cloud deployment (Docker), Computer Vision Libraries (OpenCV, PIL, Scikit-image), NLP Libraries (NLTK, Spacy)

Awards

Winner, Hackathon, CSE FEST 2019, Khulna University 2019

Winner, Hackathon, CSE FEST 2017, Khulna University 2017 **Software Engineer,** *Genuity Systems Ltd.* ☑ 2020 – 2021 | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Developed a chatbot using RASA and other NLP libraries to provide customer support and improve customer satisfaction
- Collaborated with the team to design and implement various NLP features, such as sentiment analysis and intent recognition
- Developed a speech recognition system using Kaldi for a research project.
- Conducted testing and validation to ensure the accuracy and reliability of the chatbot

Publications

Dynamic Facility Layout Problem Using Chemical Reaction Optimization, $/EEE \ \ \square$

2020

"Dynamic Facility Layout Problem Using Chemical Reaction Optimization," 2020 4th International Conference on Computer, Communication and Signal Processing (ICCCSP), Chennai, India, 2020.DOI:10.1109/ICCCSP49186.2020.9315277

Courses

Introduction to Data Science, Coursera ☑

2018

Grade: 93.75%

References

Mohammed Moinul Hasan,

Technical Manager, FinSource Limited moinul.hasan@hotmail.com, +8801732640333

Ferdous Bin Ali, *Lead Data Scientist*, RAENA hridoyferdous@yahoo.com, +8801675615851